

#### **Personal Information**

Place of Origin - Chania / Crete Date of Birth - May 14th, 1984

#### Contact



Metamorfosi, Attiki



in www.linkedin.com/in/panagiotis-gkrigkas

# **Education**

**Data Scientist Certification** Big Blue Academy

• 2020

Chief Engineer (STCW III/2) Center of Training for Merchant Navy Officers

• 2012

Second Engineer (STCW III/2) Center of Training for Merchant Navy

• 2007

Third Engineer (STCW III/2) **Greek Merchant Marine Academy** 

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

- Marine Engineering
- Proactive Maintenance
- Corrective Maintenance
- Problem Solving
- ISM/STCW/MARPOL
- ISO 9001/50001/14001
- Danaos Software
- Communication
- Microcontroller Programming
- Electronics
- Software development
- Business Intelligence tools
- HTML/SQL/Python/C++/Ladder
- Data Analytics
- AI/ML algorithms

# Language

- Greek
- English

# Panagiotis Gkrigkas

Chief Engineer (STCW III/2)

# **About**

Marine Engineer (STCW III/2 Chief Engineer C.O.C.) with more than 14 years of experience, most of which in key position roles in the engineering department. Experienced with proactive and corrective maintenance and an analytical mindset.

Passionate about continuous learning and improvement, interested in new technologies and a certified Data Scientist. Self learning developer, electronics and IoT device creator.

# **Experience**

2021 - 2022

Neda Maritime Agency Co. Ltd.

# Chief Engineer (STCW III/2)

Chief Engineer on cape size vessel with DSME B&W 6S70MC-C main engine, Hyundai Himsen auxiliary engines and Aalborg auxiliary boiler.

2017 - 2021

Neda Maritime Agency Co. Ltd.

# Second Engineer (STCW III/2)

Second Engineer on cape size vessels with DSME B&W 6S70MC-C main engine, Hyundai Himsen auxiliary engines and Aalborg auxiliary boiler.

2015 - 2017

On The Rocks Tours

## **Owner**

Tourist company, organizing excursions in Chania rural areas.

2012 - 2015

Neda Maritime Agency Co. Ltd.

### Second Engineer (STCW III/2)

Second Engineer on cape size vessel with DSME B&W 6S70MC-C main engine, Hyundai Himsen auxiliary engines and Aalborg auxiliary boiler.

2010 - 2012

Neda Maritime Agency Co. Ltd.

### Third Engineer (STCW III/2)

Third Engineer on cape size vessel with DSME B&W 6S70MC-C main engine, Hyundai Himsen auxiliary engines and Aalborg auxiliary boiler, as well as Kamsarmax vessels with MITSUI MAN/B&W 6S60MC-C7 main engine and Daihatsu auxiliary engines.

2008 - 2010

Danaos Shipping Co. Ltd

### Third Engineer (STCW III/2)

Third Engineer on container vessels.